TOM EAGLE BENG

PERSONAL PROFILE

I am a mature Engineering Graduate seeking to begin a new career in the exciting field of digital media. My experience with this began when I created a website to promote my own property services company - I only wish I had continued down that route! At university I also had programming experience, putting C+ to use in my final project. More recently I have been teaching myself HTML, CSS, SCSS, JS, jQuery and Bootstrap. I've also been learning through Google Garage. I have found this thoroughly engaging and enjoyable and wish to continue to pursue it in a professional environment. I believe I have the determination and aptitude to be highly successful given the right opportunity.



I also have 11 years' experience in the construction industry, including managing my own property services business and latterly as assistant manager for a green building company, consistently providing excellent customer service, delivering projects on time and on budget.

I have an affinity with IT and other technology and excellent numeracy and literacy. I am very excited about moving into this industry and keen to build on my knowledge with further skills and experience.

KEY INFORMATION

- 1st class degree Mechanical Engineering BEng,
- Highly IT literate: MS Office; HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, C+ Programming experience. Also experience of Image Editing with GIMP.
- High level of numeracy and literacy.
- Excellent attention to detail with conscientious attitude.

QUALIFICATIONS

- 1st class honours Mechanical Engineering UMIST (2000)
- A levels Maths (A), Physics (A), Gen Studies (A), Geography (C) 1997

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Site manager, EcoVert Solutions July 2014 to Present

In July 2014 my role was expanded to involve managing construction sites in addition to the existing responsibilities, to include training staff, liaising with clients, suppliers and

TOM EAGLE BENG

subcontractors. Checking quality of workmanship/compliance. Solving problems onsite and ensuring quality and health and safety standards are met.

Project assistant, EcoVert Solutions Oct 2012 to July 2014

EcoVert provides low energy refurbishments and new build services for commercial and domestic buildings up to PassivHaus standard.

National Trust Environment Volunteer - March 2012 - March 2013

I worked with the environmental practice advisers in Wales. My main project was to assess the NT's holiday properties for energy efficiency, and to look for opportunities for improvement.

Owner/Manager, Eagle Property Services - Chester April 2005 - October 2012 Responsible for managing and carrying out property maintenance/development contracts, ranging from minor repairs and mechanical/electrical installations to full property refurbishment. Alongside this I was responsible for all the marketing, accounting, tendering and ancillary tasks relating to the business.

ACCOMPLISHMENTS

Professional

- Site managed sustainable property refurbishment projects valued up to c£300,000
- Ran own property Maintenance Company and managed contracts valued up to £55,000. Maintained business through difficult period in the construction industry.
- Sourced, planned and coordinated groups of trades people to fully meet the project criteria.
- Learned and used MS FrontPage software/HTML/CSS to create business website
- Achieved certification under BS7671: requirements for electrical installations
- Used a wide variety of tools and equipment and skills to carry out refurbishment projects to a high standard.

Academic

- First class honours degree in Mechanical Engineering.
- Outstanding results in various subjects
- Used word processing and spreadsheet software packages to produce many technical reports to a high standard.
- Learned programming language (C+) from scratch to develop material testing equipment for university dissertation.

Personal interests

• Keen runner, cyclist and climber. Regularly participate in races around the country.